<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualization on Jeffrey W. Hollister</title>
    <link>https://jwhollister.com/tags/visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualization on Jeffrey W. Hollister</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jwhollister.com/tags/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Data Analysis in R: Lightning Demo!</title>
      <link>https://jwhollister.com/post/2015-11-06-r-gis-lightning-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwhollister.com/post/2015-11-06-r-gis-lightning-demo/</guid>
      <description>At this years NEARC meeting I decided to give a lightning talk on using R as a GIS. As I was working on this I thought, &amp;ldquo;why not try a lightning demo?&amp;rdquo; That would be better than five minutes of slides on packages and commands. But, as anyone who has done a live demo will know, they often provide unexpected challenges. Add a 5 minute limit to that, and well, some level of failure is sure to occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I finally got quickmapr on CRAN!</title>
      <link>https://jwhollister.com/post/2015-10-30-i-finally-got-quickmapr-up-on-cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwhollister.com/post/2015-10-30-i-finally-got-quickmapr-up-on-cran/</guid>
      <description>A little over 7 months ago I posted about a package that I had been working on, quickmapr. That was the pre-release version, the one that I finished up today and submitted to CRAN is a bit more polished, plots rasters a bit quicker, and is, I think, ready for wider release. It is now availble from CRAN.
The README on GitHub provides details plus some examples using a small dataset included with the package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download Shapefiles - Take 2</title>
      <link>https://jwhollister.com/post/2015-06-15-download-shapefile-reprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwhollister.com/post/2015-06-15-download-shapefile-reprise/</guid>
      <description>So back in 2013 I posted a little function I wrote for grabbing all the relevant files that make up a shapefile from a URL. Turns out it doesn’t play so well with Windows 7 or Windows 8 (HT: John Lewis). Below is a reprised version that at least works on Ubuntu 14.04 and Windows 7. Haven’t tested it beyond that and supressing the warnings to get httr::GET to not complain too much about FTP seems a bit unclean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quickmapr: An R package for mapping and interacting with spatial data</title>
      <link>https://jwhollister.com/post/2015-03-13-quickmapr-pre-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwhollister.com/post/2015-03-13-quickmapr-pre-release/</guid>
      <description>I do a lot of GIS. That used to mean firing up any one of the esri products, but over the course of the last couple of years I have done that less and less and instead fired up R.
When I first started using R for my spatial analysis work I often was left struggling with viewing the results of my analysis and could only do so with a clunky workflow of pushing my sp or raster objects out to shapefiles or tiffs and then pulling those into Arcmap.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>