<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on Jeffrey W. Hollister</title>
    <link>/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on Jeffrey W. Hollister</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My project management workflow, or, how I make the most of limited mental bandwidth</title>
      <link>/post/2018-06-20-my-workflow-or-how-i-make-the-most-of-limited-mental-bandwidth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-06-20-my-workflow-or-how-i-make-the-most-of-limited-mental-bandwidth/</guid>
      <description>Several weeks ago, there was some activity on Twitter espousing the virtues RStudio projects, including a mention of Jenny Bryan’s post on Project-oriented workflow Reading through the tweets and re-reading Jenny’s post reminded me that even though many of us use Projects or other tools to organize our work, the specifics of our toolset and workflows are still likely unique and reflect a lot of personal decisions and preferences. The other thing that struck me is that aside from Jenny’s post, I have rarely seen these types of things documented (they may be, I just blissfully unaware).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting a Category Feed Up and Running with Jekyll on Github</title>
      <link>/post/2014-10-09-category-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2014-10-09-category-feed/</guid>
      <description>Now that I have the site up and running, I am now trying to add a few category specific RSS feeds. I will say that for someone who is new to RSS (i.e. me) the feeds on Wordpress are really easy. But, since I now fancy myself somewhat of hacker, I suppose figuring out how to get a Jekyll site hosted on Github to spit these out is something I should do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colophon: jwhollister.com v0.2.0</title>
      <link>/post/2014-10-08-colophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2014-10-08-colophon/</guid>
      <description>Hard to believe that in less than a year I am now on the third version of my website. First one was me hacking at bootstrap. I knew next to nothing then, but was able to get a minimal site up and running. Since then I have learned quite a bit more about web design, Jekyll, hosting on github, and am a much better hacker than I was then (although still not a good one).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>